# Simmy Payyappilly Varghese

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# **Profile**

Full Stack Developer with 7 years of IT experience in testing and supporting multiple platforms. Recognized for being an enthusiastic learner, team player and problem solver with an eye for details. Passionate about developing apps by utilizing the newly learned technologies.

# **Projects**

#### Full Stack Bootcamp, UCLA Extension

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

Mixed Music App- A Node JS web application build using Express JS and Sequelize ( MVC) for music lovers to choose songs based on their mood and search for songs

Created Login, SignUp and Search Routes for user to search the songs, Save the Song Route to add song to user's library. Created Event Handler for play the song feature

California Road Trip Planner-Application created using HTML5,JS ,JQuery and CSS3,Bootstrap and JQ Widgets for travelers to plan their trip and find restaurants near their stops.

Created Map and markers for the coordinates using Google MAPS JS API.Created Route and directions using Direction Services of Maps API.Implemented Dialog Boxes and functionality using JQuery UI widgets .Used Yelp API to populate the nearby restaurant data.

# **Employment History**

#### Front End Engineer, Blackhawk Network, Pleasanton

JULY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Built page layouts and email templates according to customer parameters utilizing reusable code using HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Bootstrap, and JSON. Monitored and troubleshot Jenkins builds. Monitored websites utilizing Sentry and Splunk to rectify front-end-related issues.

#### Systems Support Analyst, Blackhawk Network, Pleasanton

DECEMBER 2016 - JULY 2021

Analyzed and Identified many back end high priority data issues for ETLjobs.Created and executed Test plan for the data loads.Increased efficiency and productivity of team by automating many manual process I.Developed and Maintained SQL scripts to automate data updates.

#### Technical Associate, Tech Mahindra Ltd, Pune

MARCH 2011 - MARCH 2013

Performed Functional ,Regressional and UI testing of various Siebel products .Maintained test logs and defects for failed test cases.Executed Component and E2E testing to identify interface defects at an early stage.

# Education

MS, Software Engineering, International Technological University, San Jose

AUGUST 2014 - JUNE 2016

#### **Details**

Livermore

United States

925-523-1393

simmyvarghese5@gmail.com

## Links

LinkedIn

Codepen

Github

**Portfolio** 

### **Skills**

CSS

HTML

Bootstrap 4

JavaScript

jQuery

Git

**Data Structures** 

Algorithms

SQL

Node.js

Express.js

Sequelize

React

Mongo DB

GraphQL

MERN Stack

Markdown

## **Certifications**

Full Stack Coding Certification-UCLA Ext-Present

JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures-freeCodeCamp (April 2021)